Oh, yes! You got donuts.
I already ate all the Boston Cream.
Kyle!
This place gives me the creeps.
Relax. That popsicle
hasn't moved in fifty years.
Is that normal?
No.
Someone's hacking the system.
- What?
- The containment tank is destabilizing.
He's waking up.
We need more guys.
That is all the guys.
Wait a second.
I thought we were going tubing.
Hold on. Is this a race?
You're going down!
It is my destiny to claim the throne
of Family Champion, hedgehog.
Cute. Are you sure you want to challenge
the fastest creature in the universe?
That's kind of my whole brand.
Okay, Tom and Maddie,
- count us down.
- Right!
Don't worry,
a little sibling rivalry is healthy.
Me and my brothers
did this kind of thing all the time.
Tom, your brothers are lunatics
and neither have the power
to trigger a global cataclysmic event.
That's a fair point.
Did you hear that, boys?
No cataclysmic events, okay?
Let's keep this cataclysmic-less.
- Ten-four!
- Understood, Lord of the Donuts.
Then on your marks, get set,
go!
And way out in front, to the surprise
of absolutely no one,
it's the Blue Blur, the Red-Shoed Rocket,
- the one, the only...
- Come on, Sonic!
Catch up! Yeah!
- What in the what, now?
- I am also defeating you, hedgehog!
Seriously?
All right, you know what?
Time to light the afterburners.
Look! It's a bird! It's a plane!
It's Air Hedgehog!
Yes! I did it! I...
lost? How is that even possible?
I do not lose.
I am also defeating you, hedgehog.
Okay, okay, I get it, man.
No need to rub it in.
Come on, Sonic! Catch up! Yeah!
Wait, what's going on?
Why are you guys acting like...
holograms!
Which means I remain the undefeated
speed champion of all time!
Yes! And the crowd goes wild!
But also, what's going on?
Surprise!
But wait a sec, you guys,
what is all this?
"Happy Bea Arthur Day"?
Oh, it's "Happy B-Earth-Day."
Today's the anniversary of the day
you came to Earth, bud.
It's your "Earth Day Birthday."
So the race was just a distraction...
Which I totally didn't fall for,
by the way. Good try, though...
So you could throw a party for me?
Today, we honor you, hedgehog.
If it wasn't for you,
none of us would be here right now.
Boys are right, bud.
The day you came to this planet
is the day all our lives changed forever.
And we became a family.
You guys, I don't know what to say.
Except let's party!
- All right!
- Yeah!
It's now on until the break of dawn!
Thanks for the surprise party.
It really means a lot to me.
You deserve it, pal.
No way. Is that...
What? Dude,
could you just for once walk at my speed?
Sonic!
- This is your...
- Yep. My old cave.
Oh, man.
I can't believe this is where you lived
all those years.
Hey! My state-of-the-art security system!
Still works.
Hey, bud.
What's this?
Wow.
You know, I drew that
on my first night on Earth.
I wanted to remember where I came from.
I still miss her.
You think Longclaw would be proud of me?
I know she would, pal.
Because even though you lost her
at such a young age,
you didn't let your pain
change who you are
in here.
Yeah. In my lungs.
Or your heart.
Heart, right. Yeah, makes more sense.
Not lungs, heart.
That's the thing about life, Sonic.
It's all about the choices we make.
You're gonna make some good ones and,
knowing you,
you're gonna make some bad ones.
But,
as long as you remember
to listen to your heart,
you're gonna make the right choice
when it matters the most.
Thanks.
I don't know what I'd do without you.
I'd probably be
a totally different hedgehog.
2024?
I've been trapped for fifty years?
- Move, move!
- Take positions!
Get on the ground now!
We've got you surrounded!
Why won't you leave me alone?
Take him down!
I have dishonored my marshmallow.
It's really just a question
of temperature and distance.
It's not a competition.
This is so nice.
- Peace.
- Quiet.
Finally.
Finally!
Hey! We're trying to have
a family moment down here!
- What did we do?
- Or what did they do?
- What did you do?
- I don't know. I do a lot of stuff.
Mr. and Mrs. Wachowski.
Aliens.
"Aliens"? Excuse me?
It's not like we're from
different planet... Oh, yeah, we are.
I guess we are aliens. Please continue.
I'm Director Rockwell.
There is a very dangerous situation
unfolding right now in Tokyo.
Commander Walters is requesting
Team Sonic's immediate assistance.
"Team Sonic"? Who picked that name?
Love it! 10 out of 10, no notes.
Tom and Maddie,
put the s'mores on ice
because Team Sonic is off to save the day!
Remember,
make good choices!
Good evening and welcome
to Tails Air flight 1012.
We're looking at
an on-time arrival into Tokyo.
Okay, Captain,
we got a rogue alien on the loose.
How do we find him?
Start with the giant fireball?
I love it!
Let's start with the giant fireball.
Finally, some action!
Okay, time to gear up.
Titanium handcuffs,
completely indestructible.
I don't need your silly gizmos, fox.
And you know why?
Because I am one million percent muscle.
Yes, good. You've been listening.
We're over the drop zone.
All right, here we go. Showtime!
Now, look, we don't know if it's Godzilla
or Hello Kitty down there,
but as long as we stick together,
there is nothing we can't handle.
"Team Sonic" on three.
One, two, three.
Team...
- Sonic!
- ...Knuckles!
Talk about low-budget flights.
No food or movies?
We're out of here!
- What happened here?
- Looks like GUN got their butts kicked.
Keep your eyes open. Tails, anything?
Whoa! These energy readings
are off the charts!
Look out!
One million percent.
Are you guys seeing this?
- He looks just like you.
- Impossible!
You're a colorful bunch.
Excuse me. Why do you look like me?
I don't look like you. You look like me!
Why do you look like me?
Hey, you know what?
I'll ask the questions, new hedgehog!
Who are you? Why do you look like me?
This is a waste of time.
Walk away before you get hurt.
Whoa, whoa, easy, buddy.
We don't want to fight you.
Actually, Sonic, I would like to fight.
Not now.
Why don't you
stop throwing cars at us for a second
and come down here to talk.
You jumped out of a GUN helicopter.
There's nothing to talk about.
All right, then. Enough!
Knuckles, no!
Let us talk with our fists!
Knuckles!
Knuckles? Knuckles, are you okay?
No, not really.
Who is this guy?
He is much more impressive
than the hedgehog I fought previously.
Dude, I'm standing right here.
Now, come on!
He can't take us all at once.
Okay, he took us all at once.
Weakling.
Don't try to follow me.
Sonic, I know that look.
Going after him is a bad idea.
When has that ever stopped me?
I got to ask, one hedgehog to another,
who does your highlights?
Hey! Dangerously weaving
through traffic is my thing!
Coming through!
Why are you running away?
We were just getting started.
The more you talk,
the harder I want to hit you.
Watch out!
I'm gonna throw up.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
1.21 gigawatts.
You've got to be kidding me!
Sonic!
Are you okay?
I'm fine, guys. And before you ask,
I handcuffed myself for tactical reasons
that I do not have time to explain.
You shouldn't have gone off on your own.
We're supposed to be a team.
Sorry, buddy.
I'm still working on this teamwork thing.
So now what?
Well, I'm not jumping out of
any more helicopters
until we get some answers from GUN.
We need somewhere to regroup.
I know just the place.
It's an ambush!
You'll never take us alive, foul beasts!
Calm down, Knuckles.
This is a Chao Garden.
One of the top ten must-see spots
in all of Tokyo!
It's the perfect place for us to blend in.
Are you Detective Pikachu?
Yes, he is!
He does look like a Pokémon.
"Pika, pika!"
Commander Walters!
Sonic.
Thank God you're all okay.
I'm sure you have questions.
Just a big ticked-off red and black one.
Who was that guy?
Shadow's story began
a lot like yours, Sonic.
But where you found family and friends
on this planet,
Shadow found only pain and loss.
It begins over fifty years ago
with a meteor crash
in a quiet corner of Oklahoma.
The meteorite contained a life form.
The ultimate life form.
Shadow's power... his "chaos energy"...
went far beyond any living creature.
The scientist who discovered him
believed this power
would usher in a new era for humanity.
But Shadow's power proved too dangerous.
A terrible accident destroyed the lab,
taking human lives with it.
The project leader was blamed for
the incident and imprisoned.
With the program canceled,
Shadow was a loose end
no one knew how to deal with.
Too dangerous to be walking free,
too valuable to destroy.
So I had him placed into stasis...
indefinitely.
Wait a second.
If Shadow's been on ice for fifty years,
- someone had to help him escape.
- True.
But there's only a few people in the world
who even know of Shadow's existence.
A live show? Yeah!
Get down!
Egg drones?
But Robotnik is supposed to be dead!
Konnichi-what?
I'm sorry, we already had
our big motorcycle chase for the evening.
Commander Walters!
Commander Walters, are you okay?
Sonic...
take this.
What is it?
A key
to the most powerful weapon
GUN has ever built.
You're the only one I trust
to keep it safe.
Commander Walters...
Alpha team, fan out!
Do we have eyes?
Secure the perimeter!
Medevac is en route.
His launch key is missing.
I knew they couldn't be trusted.
Why are we running from GUN?
Aren't we on the same team?
Until we get more information,
we're not trusting anyone. Follow me.
Hold it right there, Tokyo Drift!
Who are you?
It's the Goat Milker!
"It's the Goat Milker!"
Relax. I'm not here to fight.
- Then why are you here?
- And why did you free Shadow?
Are you kidding?
The last thing we want is more
super-powered hedgehogs running around.
The doctor had nothing to do with it.
And I can prove it.
Please,
join me in the crab.
And now back to La Úitima Pasión.
I have fallen in love with another.
But who, Gabriella? Tell me who!
My twin brother, Pablo?
Pablo!
¡Bastardo!
¡Buenos días, hermano!
No...
Let that be a lesson to you, Juan.
Family is a field of emotional claymores
that leave you abandoned, betrayed
and weeping while you eat cake,
which creates copious amounts
of adipose tissue
and what some calloused individuals
refer to as
man boobs.
Doctor, we have visitors.
Really?
I thought I was having
an anthropomorphic nightmare.
Where the only person
I could trust in the world
showed up with all my worst enemies
while I was in a bathrobe,
playing congas on my big, fat belly!
Sorry, sir.
I don't believe it. Eggman's alive?
And he's never looked worse.
Well, maybe
this is what not giving a damn
what you think I look like looks like.
Sir, right now we have
an even bigger problem.
Oh, come on.
There's an imposter out there
using your technology.
Imposter. That's impossi... What?
No.
My sweet mechanized spawn!
Whomever this party-pooping posse
is looking for has stolen my persona
and the precious babies from my egg sac.
Well,
I'll soon egg-xact my revenge.
You see what I did there?
It's time for the dramatic
soap-opera twist
where this Pablo reveals his Juan!
By cross-referencing
the precise coordinates
of each drone's energy spikes
I can track my babies to the imposter's
base of operations right about
there!
Sonic, I hate to say it, but I think
we're both after the same person.
Hold on, hold on.
You're not suggesting we team up with
Doctor Ro-Butt-Stink, are you?
Perhaps the fox is right.
It could be our only chance
to find this mysterious,
more impressive hedgehog.
All right, Egghead. I hate to say it,
but it looks like we're partners.
On one condition.
Dude, you have serious issues.
Let's
do this!
Suck it in!
Tinker-tailor?
I need room.
Think Elvis circa 1976.
But sir,
I don't have the proper materials.
Found some.
Resourceful.
Hey! This is a restricted area.
It's okay.
She's the professor's granddaughter.
He takes her everywhere.
Welcome to the lab, Maria.
I'm Captain Walters.
Do you know where my room is?
Yeah, down the hall and to the right.
Make yourself at home.
But let's lose the skates, okay, kiddo?
Okay.
Look out!
Wow.
Look at all those stars.
They're like diamonds.
My grandfather says
it can take hundreds of years
for the light of a star to reach Earth.
And by the time you see it,
the star might not even exist anymore.
Isn't that crazy?
A light shines
even though the star is gone.
Yeah, it does.
- I wonder which one you came from, Shadow.
- I don't know.
I don't know anything about my home.
This is your home, Shadow.
Earth.
Maria,
do you think I'm
dangerous?
What are you talking about?
The way the scientists look at me,
I can tell they're afraid.
Like I'm the horrible thing
from that movie we watched.
I don't know
what I am.
You're my friend.
And you can do or be anything you want.
Not because of your powers
but because of who you are in here.
I don't know what I'd do without you.
Professor?
It's good to see you, Shadow.
I knew you would come home.
I can't get her out of my head.
The pain,
it's too much.
And that is why we have to punish them.
Okay, I don't like you
and you don't like me.
Let's get this over with quickly.
Out of my way, dorkupine.
"Dorkupine"? Really clever.
This door is six-inch-thick solid steel
on a pressurized latch.
I'll need a moment to calculate
the molecular density
and invert the venting mechanics.
I unlocked it.
Subtle as always, fist-for-brains.
Easy, Shadow.
Those are the guests I've been expecting.
Let's give them a warm welcome.
What is this place?
It looks like a military base,
but nobody's been here for years.
I wonder if it's haunted.
Haunted? Nobody said anything
about being haunted.
What's the matter? You afraid of ghosts?
Nothing scares an Echidna warrior.
Yeah. Do you remember
what happened last movie night?
Let go, let go, let go!
There is no such thing
as a friendly ghost.
So which way do we go?
I know! We should split up.
Everyone with hideous, brightly-colored
fur take the left and the middle.
Stone and I will go right.
No, no, no.
I'm not letting you out of my sight.
Tails, you and Stone go left.
Knuckles, you take the middle.
Eggman, you and me go right.
By all means.
We could use some time together
to work on your trust issues.
You know what? You're right.
I should be more trusting.
I mean,
you've only tried to kill me twice!
Just a dark, creepy hallway.
Nothing to be afraid of.
You hear that, ghost?
You don't frighten me!
Get a grip.
Boo.
I'm just gonna come right out
and say this:
- You're adorable.
- Thanks.
So, what's it like
being Sonic's assistant?
You have a daily routine?
Paid time off? Benefits?
I'm not Sonic's assistant.
We're teammates.
He's the leader, Knuckles is the muscle,
and I'm the gadget guy.
We all have a role to play.
That's what makes the team so special!
That and the fact we're best friends.
You are?
Well, yeah.
Just like you and Eggman, right?
Yeah.
Of course! Yes.
Me and the doctor, best of friends.
That's definitely what we are.
Look at all this stuff.
This was more than
just a military base or a lab.
It was a home. People lived here.
He had a family.
Is that what I smell?
The stench of domestic harmony?
You ever wonder what your life would have
been like if you had a family?
No.
Maybe you wouldn't have gone
full supervillain.
I had no parents, no aunts, no uncles.
And something about my attitude renders me
undesirable to all possible genders.
My future is a cul-de-sac!
The Robotnik name ends
avec moi.
Yes, I know French.
Is this where you grew up, Shadow?
No wonder you're so mad.
This place could really use
a beanbag chair and some comic books.
What happened here?
I'm tired of giving you warnings!
Where'd you go, hedgehog?
I wasn't finished trauma dumping.
My darlings!
My eggy weggies!
Memories
Light the corners
Of my mind
Misty watercolor
Memories
Of the way
We weren't
I... don't believe it.
Don't you?
- It's impossible.
- Is it?
- It couldn't be.
- Couldn't it?
- I'm...
- Are you?
Imposter!
You stole my babies!
But they know who their real daddy is,
drone-napper!
Magnificent creations, my boy.
I borrowed them to lure you here
and reunite our family.
You see, Ivo...
I'm your grandfather:
Gerald Robotnik.
My grandfather?
But how? And why?
And who did what with whom?
You hail from an ancestry of excellence,
tied directly à moi.
Yes, I know French.
You do look like me.
But fatter. And older.
And there's that funny smell.
But the resemblance is uncanny.
It's as if...
We're two characters in a movie
being played by the same actor.
- But I need real proof!
- Ivo!
We have very little time.
But I could field a couple of queries.
Name the most elegant formula
in mathematics.
Euler's Identity.
E to the I times pi plus one equals zilch.
European capitals arranged alphabetically
by the fourth letter.
Riga, Monaco, Sarajevo, Tirana.
The speed of light
divided by the speed of sound
divided by the speed of the bus
in the movie Speed.
17,893.33333.
- Rounding up?
- 17,894 mph.
And, for all the marbles...
Good. I lost mine.
A rare lung disease
and the longest word
in the English dictionary.
Pneumonoultramicroscopic
silicovolcanoconiosis!
- Pap-pap!
- In the saggy flesh.
But looking pretty good
for a hundred and ten.
Grampy-poo.
Where have you been my entire life?
Wait.
Locked in a top-secret prison
for the last fifty years.
Made it kind of hard
to send Christmas cards.
Now,
you're probably wondering
why I brought you here.
You didn't bring me here!
I used my unparalleled intellect
to track you down.
Per the plan I concocted
with my unparalleled intellect.
You'll see.
I have the answer to everything.
Come on, kiddo.
Oh, no. Oh, no, no.
Someone tell me this is some kind of
concussion-induced nightmare.
There's two Eggmen now?
Double your villains, double your fun!
Two Robotniks are way worse than one.
Chest bump? No.
Stone, why are you tied up?
Do that on your own time. You sicken me.
You must be the long-lost grandson.
And you must be another stinking hedgehog.
So you're the one behind all this.
- The Shadow breakout.
- The attack on Walters.
That musty old-man smell.
How dare you insult me
with your unsolicited exposition!
Shadow, get the key.
Where is it?
Ha! Good one, Hot Topic.
Do you really think we'd be that stupid,
to bring the key right to you?
Yep, we're that stupid.
GUN took everything from us. And now
we are going to take everything from them.
With this.
My masterpiece of malevolence:
The Eclipse Cannon.
In exchange for my freedom,
I gave GUN the most powerful weapon
mankind has ever seen,
capable of delivering a precision strike
anywhere on Earth.
Our first target:
GUN Headquarters.
But firing a weapon that powerful
could threaten millions of innocent lives!
Yeah, tera-bite me.
This is one of two keys required
to launch the Eclipse Cannon.
The other is locked
inside GUN headquarters.
Once we have both,
I will take rightful control of my weapon.
I'm in.
Holy crab!
Spacious and crustaceous.
Thank you so much for inspiring
this little adventure.
It really worked out for me.
And you wonder why I have trust issues!
Shadow, wait! Don't do this.
I know you're hurting, but don't let that
change who you are inside.
I've spent fifty years
reliving what they did to her.
This is who I am inside.
Nice magic marble. Real scary.
That actually is real scary!
It's a mini black hole! It's going to
suck in all the matter in this base!
Fear not, friends.
Even my teeth are muscles!
Sonic, try to reach one of my rings!
Got one.
Check this out. Trick shot!
Come on.
Come on!
Yeah! Yes!
Yikes.
Somebody better call Google Maps.
I've spent years
trying to cleanse the cosmos
of that spiny blue speed freak.
And you did it...
in one afternoon.
There's nothing we can't destroy together,
my boy.
Charting route to GUN Headquarters
in London, sirs.
ETA four hours
as the crab flies.
By all accounts, we're ahead of schedule.
We should take this time
to get to know each other better.
Wow. What?
You mean
spend some quality time?
You've waited for this your whole life.
How would you choose to spend one
perfect day with your new grand pal?
And done!
- Masterpiece. Look at that.
- Yay!
It's really been great
having time to ourselves.
Right. Absolutely. I just feel so relaxed,
you know? Clearheaded.
Look at all these new interests we found.
- I know, so many hobbies.
- So many!
After the action and adventure
of the last few years,
- well, I could get used to this.
- Same.
Tom! Maddie!
We need your help on a super...
- Knuckles, do you mind?
- Excuse me.
Tom! Maddie! We need your help
on a super-dangerous top-secret mission!
- Thank God. Yeah, we're in.
- Let's go.
Really? You're in? Just like that?
Yes. It was getting so boring
without you guys here.
- No offense.
- No, none taken.
I mean, whatever crazy plan
you're cooking up, the answer's yes.
Great. But first things first:
What is that?
This is
Li'l Tom! Isn't he great?
I told you to get rid of that.
It's very creepy.
I told him to get rid of you.
- Okay, that's crossing a line there.
- You are in so much trouble.
Okay, this is it. The belly of the beast.
GUN Headquarters in London.
Tom, we're finally gonna
get to see London together.
I told you we'd get there someday, baby.
Okay. So here's the plan.
I run in superfast,
fly over that water, no problem,
and right when I get to the...
What just happened?
Congratulations. You just got incinerated
by their energy shield.
We'll need to shut it down by planting
a USB drive in their server room
that will give me full control over it.
That's what we need you two for.
Couple of badass spies,
that's what we are.
Mr. and Mrs. Smith.
Once we disable the shield,
you'll face the laser hall.
These high-density bad boys
will cut you into tiny pieces.
And cut those pieces
into even tinier pieces!
Once again?
- Can't we just get Tom Cruise to do this?
- Nope.
Because not even he
could break into the vault.
Why is it empty in there?
Because we have no idea
what's on the other side of that door.
To prevent the vault
from ever being accessed by a ring,
all images and schematics
have been wiped from GUN's database.
So for the last leg of this heist...
We're going in blind.
Sorry.
Okay, I'm just gonna say it.
It sounds like this plan would work
a heck of a lot better
if Sonic used the Master Emerald
to go Golden God mode
to get the key.
No way, Maddie. The Master Emerald
is too powerful to ever use again.
We made a promise to each other
to keep it hidden.
In a location only Knuckles knows.
As guardian of the Master Emerald,
anyone who tries
to take it away for any reason
will become a sworn enemy.
Okay, okay! Sheesh! No need
to get all growly on me, buddy.
You guys are always telling us
to make good choices.
Well, this is the right choice.
Okay.
I guess we're going to...
London, baby!
GUN Headquarters is right there.
Let me go in, get the key
and destroy anyone in my way!
I want revenge.
Patience, Shadow.
Just let us handle this,
and I promise you'll have revenge
on a scale you couldn't possibly imagine.
Come on, Granddaddy-O,
we've got dirt to do!
Suits.
Right here, sir.
Stone, babysit the hedgehog.
Keep the crab on a low boil.
It's time for more family bonding.
Come on, Shadow.
Got fresh avocados in the crab.
We'll make guac.
Revenge Guac!
Guys, are you ready for me yet?
I've been waiting here all day.
Sonic, we literally just started.
Tom, Maddie,
are you in position and ready?
- We were born ready.
- Let's do this.
Knuckles, how about you?
I have taken my perch
atop the giant clock.
Now, where is this glass
I'm supposed to break?
Actually, Knucks, your job is
to "Break Glass in Case of Emergency."
Understood. I will shatter this glass
like the jaw of a vile foe.
In case of emergency.
I will pulverize it like the skull
of a loathsome rival!
Just to be clear, the "emergency"
is the important part.
The glass will beg for mercy
under the shadow of my mighty fists!
Guys, remember, we're a team. Let's focus.
- Please.
- You know what? Let's move on.
All right, everyone knows what to do.
Tom and Maddie,
you guys plant the USB drive.
I'll disable the traps.
Sonic will snag the launch key.
And Knuckles, you stand by to...
Break glass in case of emergency.
See? He gets it.
Then we're all set.
Hologram time.
You go first.
Tom, it's me, Rachel!
Can you believe it?
We're both in London together.
Have you met your sister? Try again.
Unless you're not up for this mission.
Yeah, maybe you want to be back
in Green Hills, baking sourdough.
- Thomas Michael Wachowski!
- Yeah?
You brought aliens to my wedding,
punched out my husband
and buried me in an avalanche.
Your day of reckoning is at hand!
Yeah, that's perfect.
Okay, now for her better half.
My name is Randall,
and I am too much to handle!
Welcome to the gun show!
Baby, would you describe me
as jacked, juiced
or shredded?
I would describe your head as swollen.
Let's get to work.
Agent Randall Handel.
I'm here to have lunch
with my lovely wife, Rachel.
I'm sorry, Agent Handel,
this facility's currently locked down.
Command-level clearance only.
One minute.
Tails,
we have a problem here.
Wow, they must have tightened security
after Shadow's escape.
I got this.
You must be new here.
Allow me to introduce myself.
My name is Rachel.
Rachel Gonnagetyoufired.
Do you know what GUN stands for?
Of course. Guardian Units...
Getting. Ultra. Nasty.
Do you want me
to get ultra nasty?
Nasty nasty?
- No, ma'am.
- Okay, then.
Then go ahead
and take those little sad fingers
and start tippity type-type-typing!
That's right, go on.
Sorry for the inconvenience, ma'am.
That's what I thought!
My God, I love being Rachel!
- Did it work?
- Oh, yeah.
Ouch!
Director Rockwell
seeking access to the server room.
Just one moment, ma'am.
Oh, no. It's her. It's the real her!
- The incident in Colorado?
- We're still assessing.
What do you mean, still assessing?
- What do we do?
- Quick, change faces!
Okay. Did it work? Who am I?
What's going on?
Why are you looking at me like that?
What am I doing wrong?
Aye, aye, Captain!
"Aye, aye, Captain"? Who are you, Popeye?
- I panicked! I was panicking!
- Jeez!
Get it together!
Okay, Tails, what are we looking for?
The security server is in the 7th row,
23rd cabinet.
Are you guys finished yet?
This is taking forever.
Uh-oh.
Has the time come to break the glass?
Or at least break something?
All right, hang tight, guys.
Maddie's about to insert the drive
Ready?
Three,
two,
one.
Go.
- It didn't work.
- Did you put it in the right way?
- Try punching it.
- Do not try punching it.
- Take it out and blow on it.
- Yes!
Come on, Tom.
There's absolutely no scientific evidence
to support...
Never mind. It worked!
- Little trick from the nineties.
- I mean, best decade ever. Right?
I'm shutting down the outside sensors now.
Yes!
Hold on.
Is there supposed to be
another USB drive here?
One with a giant mustache on it?
Oh, no.
I've got two heat signatures
en route to the vault.
Which can only mean...
The Robotniks have entered the chat.
Wait.
Poppyseed?
Grand-geezer?
¿Dónde está?
I'm right here.
If you weren't family,
I could have gut you like a pheasant.
I mean, try to keep up.
And now back to La Úitima Pasión.
Úitima Pasión
can only belong to one.
No.
It can only belong to Juan!
Gabriella should kill them both.
She's not a prize to be won.
"Kill this. Murder that."
You need to lighten up, Shadow.
We're about to rule the world.
When we're done,
there won't be anything left to rule.
That is dark. Even for you.
What are you and the professor up to?
Hello! What's this?
I knew I saw an outside signal!
Cheerio!
I guess someone forgot to flush.
What now, my cunning cohort?
Just a little teamwork!
Hey,
the lasers
don't seem to be penetrating my suit.
They're conforming to the shape
of my bodacious bod.
Of course.
I designed these suits to create a field
of laser-bending thermal distortion.
Wasn't sure it would work till now.
You're heartless, son.
Rotten to the core.
I'm so proud.
So now we can just dance right through.
That sounds like a challenge.
My finger is on the button
Push the button
The Robotniks are almost at the vault!
We're out of time. I'm going.
No, Sonic!
I haven't disabled the traps yet!
Too late!
Look at me! I'm running
on the wrong side of the road!
Well, I got to take in the sights.
Paul, John, George, the other one!
Loud American coming through!
Excuse me. Pardon me.
'Ello, guv'nor! Which way to Hogwarts?
Hear ye, hear ye!
Sonic the Hedgehog wants a cuppa tea!
Hold this for me, please.
You're not gonna make it!
I can make it.
I'm gonna make it.
I'm not gonna make it.
I'm not gonna make it!
Made it!
Excuse me. Coming through.
No time for autographs. Got to go, bye!
Our destiny awaits.
Stop right there, Roboscum!
- Let's do this!
- Copy!
Too slow, Eggmen.
Now if you don't mind,
I've got to get that key.
My feet.
Why can't I use my beautiful feet?
Because
this vault is armed with variable gravity.
No kidding.
Green goes up,
and red takes you down hard.
Rockwell, listen to me.
The Robotniks are planning to...
They're planning on stealing
a second key, just like you are?
Yes, I'm aware.
I called it the second
Commander Walters was attacked.
So,
thank you for taking the bait
and falling right into my trap.
I don't believe this.
I know, grandson.
A woman in the military!
Let's go.
Go, positions!
Full perimeter.
Robotnik.
Going full spandex, huh? Who's the fossil?
That's my grandfather,
you dough-eating dimbecile.
- Who are they?
- A couple of bleeding hearts
here to rescue
their emotional-support animals.
Enough! It's over.
The only way you're leaving here
is in handcuffs.
There is no other way out.
You know,
there might be one other way out.
And what is that supposed to mean?
Hey, big guy, I think it's time to...
Break glass in case of emergency!
Nothing can stop Team Knuckles!
Open fire!
Knuckles, turn this stuff off!
- Hurry!
- On it.
Uh-oh.
See how you like it!
- Can you move?
- No, not at all.
- Tails, can you?
- No, I'm stuck.
We might be here a while.
Where's the key?
- What was that?
- We may have a problem.
No, no, no!
I'm moving.
I'm moving!
You go get it, grandson!
Hey!
No. No, no!
I'm almost there!
Sonic!
That was so not worth it!
- You okay?
- Yeah. You good?
Sonic! Hey.
Sonic, 1. Concrete boulder, 0.
Thanks for the save.
Cutting it a little close,
don't you think?
Secure the room!
She's got the key.
I got an idea.
Commander Walters.
Sir,
- you're...
- Still alive?
I'll die before I let that key
fall into the wrong hands.
Thanks for keeping it safe.
I'll take it from here.
That's an order, Director Rockwell.
Now, organize the reinforcements.
Yes, sir.
Guys, guys, I got the key.
I repeat, I got the key.
Now let's get out of here.
Commander Walters.
No, no. No. Wait!
What?
Tom! Everyone's clear! Come on, let's go!
You. What are you...
Tom!
Tom. Tom, what happened?
Speak to me.
Come on, come on, it's gonna be okay.
Please, please, please get up.
Hey, come on, please wake up.
Wake up, wake up, come on.
Wake up, wake up, wake up!
Maria.
What did you do?
What I had to.
Oh, my God. Tom!
Help me up, kid.
Freeze! Don't move!
Any tricks up your sleeve,
Captain Grandtastic?
We got what we came for.
Great job, Shadow.
We have both keys.
So where's your little science project?
It's closer than you think, my boy.
Welcome to my masterpiece!
I must hand it to GUN.
They built her to my exact specifications.
It's...
remarkable!
- Astounding!
- Yes.
That's my genius grand-genome!
And I have one more surprise.
It's a new suit!
Gee.
I'm a chip off the old block
I'm a chip off the old block!
What do you want, Stone? I'm busy.
Doctor, I have a bad feeling about this.
I don't think your grandfather's been
completely honest with us.
It was something Shadow said.
There's more to their plan.
How dare you!
You have been jealous of my long-lost
grand-Pop-Tart since the very beginning!
I no longer require
your obsequious groveling.
Consider this your notice of termination.
Your letter of reference
will be I for Loser.
Of course, I'll expect you to stay on
until you've been successfully cloned.
But you and I are done!
Like a blackened catfish dinner!
Sir, it's too dangerous
and I'm not there to protect you.
- I already lost you once! I...
- Unsubscribe. Blocked and reported.
I can't lose you again.
Do the honors,
grandson.
Here we go.
It'll be okay, Sonic.
It'll be okay?
Tom is fighting for his life
and you think it'll be okay?
The fox is simply trying to comfort you.
Comfort's not what I need right now.
I need to stop them.
By any means necessary.
Wait, you don't mean...
The Master Emerald.
The Emerald must never be
wielded for vengeance.
Not ever!
We swore a sacred oath.
Don't talk to me about oaths. Not now!
But you told Tom using the Emerald
wasn't the right choice.
Well, now it's the only choice.
And if neither of you have the guts
to help me, then I'll do it alone.
But I thought the three of us were a team.
I thought that's what made us special.
I'm not asking you twice, Knuckles.
Where is the Master Emerald?
Your heart is being consumed
by anger, hedgehog.
You are in no condition
to make decisions right now.
I know you're upset about Tom. We all are.
Last chance.
Where is it?
Don't do this.
Part of our oath is to trust each other.
And I must abide by that promise,
even if you have chosen to break it.
But heed this warning:
The Master Emerald is guarded
by a fearsome warrior.
And to seize this ultimate power,
you will have to go
through him.
Okay, Wade, all comes down to this.
Last few seconds.
Whipple down the ice.
He shoots. He scores!
Wade Whipple is a champion again!
Oh, hey, Sonic. See my goal?
Pretty sick, right?
I'm here for the Emerald.
Look, Sonic, I'm sorry.
I promised to guard this emerald
with my life.
I will do whatever it takes...
Well, I tried.
Sonic!
So bright!
This is an urgent
national emergency broadcast.
A spacecraft designed by the agency GUN
has been hijacked and launched
out of the River Thames.
All residents are urged
to seek immediate shelter.
It's time, Shadow.
Professor, is this really
what Maria would have wanted?
The question isn't
what Maria would have wanted.
It's what do they deserve.
Remember what she meant to us.
Remember what they took from us.
Kids!
We have to go, now!
They want to take Shadow
away from us, Maria!
Hey! Hey! What are you doing?
Those are children.
- We've got our orders, Walters!
- Stand down!
Maria!
Excuse me, Grand Paso Doble.
What is that thermonuclear gerbil doing?
Infusing the core
with chaos energy.
That's my little secret.
The Eclipse Cannon is about to turn
this planet into a flaming pile of rubble,
wiping out everything
in a 25,000-mile radius.
Including us.
What?
We can't annihilate the Earth!
By combining our genius,
we can rule humanity
together!
Humanity is a failed experiment.
If anyone should know that, it's you.
All your life,
you've been rejected by this world.
You have nothing down there.
No one who cares about you.
But I have you now.
We're family.
We have each other.
Ivo,
you're no Maria.
The moment I lost her,
my family was gone forever!
The only way to give Maria's life meaning
is to destroy the world
that took her from me.
So I'm burning it all down!
It's done.
Good work, Shadow.
I'm prepping the firing sequence.
The weapon will be fully charged
in ten minutes.
It's almost finished, Maria.
You will have justice.
What is that?
Is GUN launching missiles at us?
Impossible. It's moving too fast.
It's him.
You hurt my family. This ends now!
Now you know my anger.
The pain I've felt for fifty years.
And you've made the same choice I did.
I'm nothing like you!
We'll see.
Show yourself, coward!
You were right about one thing.
This ends now.
What's happening?
Where are they?
- Up there.
- Where?
Higher.
Left yourself open.
Ivo! What are you doing?
Thwarting your evil plan!
- Not the mustache!
- Agreed.
Let go on three. One, two, three!
A nano-fist.
I haven't seen that since I hate-watched
Green Lantern in 2011.
I was saving it for Comic-Con,
but now there won't be a Comic-Con!
Why are you alone?
Where are your friends?
They tried to stop you, didn't they?
But you came anyway.
Your anger was too much.
What kind of hero abandons his friends
to pursue revenge?
Abandons his family!
Don't you dare talk about my family.
And here I thought you cared for them.
Especially the one... What's his name?
Tom?
Go ahead. Finish it!
What are you waiting for? Do it!
I'm right here!
You didn't let your pain
change who you are
in here.
This is not who I am.
What are you doing?
You won. Take your revenge.
There are no winners with revenge.
Wow.
Look at all those stars.
They're like diamonds.
The last time
I sat beneath stars like this,
I was with her.
I've felt this pain for so long.
It's all I know.
When I lost Longclaw,
I felt the same way.
Did your pain eventually go away?
No.
But in time, I learned there's something
even more powerful than pain.
The love we felt for each other.
That's what you need to hold onto, Shadow.
Maria might be gone,
but your love will always remain.
"The light shines
even though the star is gone."
This whole mess is my fault.
I've been so blinded by rage, I thought
I had no choice.
You always have a choice.
But making the right one is never easy.
One more thing I learned is that
when you really screw something up,
you can't fix it on your own.
Gotta go fast.
Don't tell me you've got a catchphrase.
That's right, new hedgehog.
And everyone loves it.
I will not try
to stop my elders from
destroying the world!
Playtime is over.
There's no going back now.
Set up defense.
Damn you, autocorrect!
Mantis!
I'm right here, arach-nerd.
That's what I call mantis-scaping.
That's elder abuse!
Alert! Alert! Alert!
Shadow,
I see you've chosen betrayal.
And you were once so useful to me.
Ready to recycle some tin cans?
Just try to keep up.
Please, Grampsy,
don't do this!
Sorry, kiddo.
Bring Your Grandkid to Work Day is over.
Any last words?
Just one thing
that I never thought I'd say.
What is it?
"I love you"?
No.
It was something even better.
But I'm not gonna say it
if that's the way you're gonna be.
Okay. Bye.
Grandchildren.
All the fun
and none of the responsibility.
Who said life was pointless?
Oh, right. You did.
Victory!
Say what you want about my granddad,
he made one hell of a bug zapper.
We got to stop that laser!
I knew there was something
I was forgetting.
We're out of time.
The cannon is about to fire!
Where are you?
You know, just making friends.
They're all yours.
Follow me!
Now, this might hurt a little!
So this was your plan?
Yeah.
Would someone mind
shutting down the giant death ray?
We can't stop the cannon from firing,
but we can steer it away from the Earth.
- Coming around to starboard.
- Aye, aye, Doc.
Here we go.
It's a little tight.
Definitely not power steering.
Keep turning.
Jump in anytime here, guys!
Can't hold much longer.
Yes!
I did it! I did it!
Look what you did!
- Hey, look down there!
- Sonic!
Knuckles, please tell me you have a...
Last one.
Let's make it count.
Ready for a little base of ball?
Deep breath.
One, two, three!
- Really!
- What's happening?
The reactor core is overloading.
It's only a matter of time
before it blows.
So what does that mean for Earth?
A radioactive atmosphere.
Rain that kills the crops
and melts your flesh.
Other than that...
We're not done here!
You try to stabilize the reactor.
Buy me some time.
I'll push the station away from Earth
before it explodes.
This is our last chance
to do the right thing.
Core integrity failing.
I've got you, Sonic!
Initializing reactor core stabilizers.
This is Doctor Ivo Robotnik,
dedicating my final livestream
to one very special henchman:
Agent Stone.
No, no. Doctor, wait!
If I can't rule the world,
I might as well save it
for the one and only person
who ever cared about me.
Don't do this, Doctor, please!
Stone, you were more than
a sycophant to me.
You were
a syco-friend.
I'll miss your lattes
with steamed Austrian goat milk.
I love the way you make them!
So, I guess there's only one thing
left to say.
It's been a real drag.
Thanks for nothing.
Sonic, look.
Shadow and Robotnik.
They sacrificed themselves
to save everyone.
You always have a choice.
Guys, I'm really sorry
for running off like that.
I shouldn't have left you behind.
The truth is,
you're the best teammates
a hedgehog could ever ask for.
And the best friends.
Can you ever forgive me?
Team Sonic?
How about just "team"?
Goodbye, Doctor.
Big finish.
Now that's what I call teamwork.
Okay! It's ready!
Knuckles, how could you?
Gotta be faster than that!
Give me a break.
Still moving a little slow over here.
- Donut Lord!
- Yay!
- Okay, Knuckles, that's...
- I am having the love.
Get in here, Ozzy.
It's great to be back together.
We're stronger than ever.
And nothing is gonna stand in our way.
Except that one piece
of unfinished business.
And way out in front, to the surprise
of absolutely no one, it's the Blue Blur!
Often imitated, never duplicated,
the one, the only...
Let's do this!
Yeah!
All right, boys, try and keep up.
Sonic the Hedgehog
is Family Champion once again!
Tails?
Knuckles?
Okay. Yeah, I overshot the finish line.
Okay, so how do I get back?
Pro tip:
If you're gonna take a shot at the
fastest creature in the universe...
you'd better not miss.
I'm flattered by the cosplay,
but you got a few details wrong.
I can't blame you, though.
It's hard to copy perfection.
That's a neat trick.
What? Who are you?